

CHRISTOPHE THIEBAUD

HEBELSTRASSE 2, HOCKENHEIM, 68766, GERMANY +49 176 81 20 33 24 CHRISTOPHE.THIEBAUD@AEQUOLOGICA.NET

I have been developing software since 1987, filling a number of different roles including Architect, People Manager, Project Manager, Lead Developer and Outside Advisor. What energizes me? A challenging position where I am able to build on decades of experience in the **creativity** + **technical expertise** + **people ecology** magical bundle to deliver truly beautiful software.

I am actively looking for a position in either **France**, or **Italy**, or ... both ©











EXPERIENCE

ARCHITECT

SAP, WALLDORF, GERMANY

Hard skills: SAP Cloud Platform (CloudFoundry & Neo); Microservices; Git & Github; Jenkins & Travis; Docker; Continuous Deployment.

Soft skills: Internal Instructor ("Continuous Integration & DevOps" course); DevOps; Agile Processes & Scrum.

November 2010 - Present

MANAGER

BUSINESS OBJECTS, PARIS, FRANCE

Hard skills: REST API design; System Performance Management.

Soft skills: Managing People; Managing Customer Escalation; Rolling out Engineering Processes and Tools, Worldwide.

February 2005 - November 2010

TEAM LEAD

UNIMATICA, BOLOGNA, ITALY

Hard skills: Linux & shell programming; Java; Javascript; HTTP & HTML & CSS; Web Servers (Tomcat & Websphere); Maven; XML; Digital Signature.

Soft skills: Web UI Design; Using and contributing to open source software.

January 2000 - February 2005

CONSULTANT

SELF-EMPLOYED, BOLOGNA, ITALY

Hard skills: Graph Algorithms; Game Programming; Macintosh Programming.

Soft skills: Selling myself; Selling one same software component to multiple customers.

September 1995 - January 2000

PROJECT MANAGER

EUROLOG, MUNICH, GERMANY

Hard skills: n/a.

Soft skills: Juggling with external contractors; Juggling with internal politics.

July 1993 - July 1995

CODER

DATAID & COMELOG (SOFTWARE HOUSES), PARIS, FRANCE

Hard skills: Windows & OS/2 SDKs; C & C++; Relational Databases & SQL; System Integration.

Soft skills: Humility (being sold to customers as OOP guru); Team Lead.

July 1987 - July 1993

SUPPORT TECHNICIAN

ISI (HARDWARE RESELLER), PARIS, FRANCE

Hard skills: Everything (answering a wild variety of questions at the hot-line).

Soft skills: The Customer Is Always Right.

June 1986 - July 1987

EDUCATION

INSEAD, FONTAINEBLEAU, FRANCE

MBA

Finance

January 1992 - December 1992

CENTRE DE FORMATION BULL, MARNE LA VALLEE, FRANCE

PROGRAMMER ANALYST

Warnier Structured Programming August 1985 - May 1986

ÉCOLE NORMALE DE MUSIQUE DE PARIS

DIPLÔME D'EXÉCUTION

Guitar

September 1978 - June 1982

LYCÉE POINCARÉ, NANCY, FRANCE

CLASSES PRÉPARATOIRES AUX GRANDES ECOLES

Mathématiques supérieures

September 1977 - June 1978

SKILLS

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES & TOOLS















PROCESSES

- ✓ Multi-cultural environment
- ✓ Agile Development & Scrum

LANGUAGES

- French, mother tongue
- English, fluent
- Italian, fluent
- & German, basic

INTERESTS

MUSIC

In addition to being a geek, I am a fine guitar player, with a strong focus on JS Bach music (google for Thiebaud+Bach).



ಾ BIKE

~ 4000 kms per year, mostly commuting.



FAVOURITE QUOTES

- $^{\rm w}$ Why program by hand in 5 days what you can spend 5 years of your life automating ? » Terence Parr
- « So convenient a thing it is to be a reasonable creature, since it enables one to find or make a reason for everything one has a mind to do. »

Benjamin Franklin

 $\label{eq:control_control} \mbox{$^{\prime}$ Triple-double-quoted strings, with the addition that they are multiline, like the triple-single-quoted strings. $^{\prime}$ }$

Groovy programming language documentation

« Without the ball, you can't win. » Johan Cruyff

AWARDS & CERTIFICATIONS

Y Business Objects Leadership Award



Proud to be a jgrapht contributor (google for thiebaud+jgrapht).

